Guide to the Carlyle Marney Papers, 1899-1979 RL.00848
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Carlyle Marney papers
1899-1979
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Marney, Carlyle, 1916-1978
RL.00848
58 Linear Feet
Approx. 45,000 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Audiovisual originals are closed to use. Use copies may be available in the collection - see individual listings. Otherwise, Technical Services staff need to produce use copies before contents can be accessed.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The papers of Carlyle Marney (1916-1978), clergyman and author, were purchased by the Rubenstein Library in 1979. Addition 2015-0140 was transferred from the Duke Divinity Library. Addition 2021-0013 was a gift from Bruce Johnson.
Biographical Note
1916, July 8 Born, Harriman, Tennessee.
1938 A.B., Carson Newman College.
1940, June 20 Married Rita Elizabeth Christopher.
1941 Ordained to ministry of Baptist Church.
1943 Th.M., Southern Baptist Theological Seminary.
1946 Th.D., Southern Baptist Theological Seminary.
1948-1958 Pastor of First Baptist Church, Austin, Texas.
1951 Visiting Professor in Homiletics, Austin Presbyterian Seminary
1952-1957 Professor of Christian Ethics, Austin Presbyterian Seminary.
1958-1967 Pastor of Myers Park Baptist Church, Charlotte, N. C.
1963 Litt.D., Wake Forest College.
1964 D.D., Johnson C. Smith University.
1967 Member, President's National Advisory Commission on Rural Poverty. D.D., Kalamazoo College
1967-1968 Vice President, National Council of Churches.
1967-1978 Founder and Director of Interpreters' House, Lake Junaluska, N. C.
1972-1978 Adjunct Professor at Duke Divinity School.
1976 Trustee, The Christian Century Foundation. D.D., University of Glasgow, Scotland. Conquest Chair in Humanities, Virginia Military Institute
1978, July 3 Died, Lake Junaluska, N. C.
Collection Overview
The papers of Carlyle Marney span the years 1899-1979, although the bulk of the collection begins in the late 1950s. Included are correspondence, drafts of writings and sermons, press releases, leaflets, pamphlets, bulletins, financial records, clippings, newsletters, calendars, reports, course materials, minutes, printed material, notes, pictures, tapes, and films. Reflected in the papers is information on rural poverty, the American Baptist Convention, the Baptist Church, especially in Texas and North Carolina, Christian writings, Abingdon Press, which published many of Marney's books, and racial prejudice. Concerning prejudice see in particular the Writings and Speeches Series: Marney (Structures of Prejudice) and the Correspondence Series (Church and Race Conference).
The principal focus of the collection is Marney's professional career as a Baptist clergyman, serving two lengthy pastorates at First Baptist Church in Austin, Texas (1948-1958), and at Myers Park Baptist Church in Charlotte, North Carolina (1958-1967), and as Founder-Director of Interpreters' House, an ecumenical center of study and work at Lake Junaluska, N.C. (1967-1978). He divided his duties to eventually develop a tripartite profession as a pastor, author, and speaker. He transcended his Southern roots to attain a national reputation as a speaker and theologian. The collection illuminates Marney as an independent and controversial figure within the Southern Baptist Church. One of the hallmarks of his ministry, which separated him from most Southern Baptists, was his ecumenical focus. According to his biographer, John J. Carey, Marney sought to be a force for Baptist renewal and to broaden the ecclesiastical and theological bases of the Southern Baptists. ยน
The Correspondence Series, Writings and Speeches Series, and Engagements Series form the major groups in the collection. The Correspondence Series, which comprises almost one-third of the bulk of the collection, consists chiefly of professional correspondence, but there is also a group of folders for Marney family members. Prominent correspondents include James T. Cleland, William Sloan Coffin, Pope A. Duncan, Findley Edge, Harry Golden, William J. Kilgore, Martin Luther King, Jr., Karl Menninger, Bill Moyers, Guy Ranson, and Elton Trueblood. Abingdon Press and the American Baptist Convention also have major files in this series. The Association of Southern Baptists for Scouting, Christian Century Foundation, and the Myers Park Baptist Church are other organizations represented in this series. The above-named topics also appear under appropriate topical headings in the Subject Files Series. There are also files in the Correspondence Series for the Church and Race Conference (Charlotte, N. C., 1965) and the God is Dead movement.
Both published and unpublished works appear in the Writings and Speeches Series. Marney was the author of twelve books and contributed articles to various theological journals; other single sermons appear in various anthologies. Most of his books were published by Abingdon Press, a Methodist publisher. There is also a copy of the book published in 1953, These Things Remain, as well as television programs, 1954, under the same title. Included in this series are the texts of unpublished books, such as City of Light/City of Wilderness, Great Encounter, Recovery of the Church, and Tragic Man/Tragic House.
In the files of writings of other persons are works of Karl Menninger and Guy Ranson, who also appear in Marney's correspondence. Other writers appearing in this section are Rufus Carrollton Harris, William Jackson Kilgore, Franklin Hamlin Littell, John David Maguire, Orval Hobart Mowrer, H. Richard Niebuhr, Schubert Miles Ogden, Clyde Penrose St. Amant, and John Egnar Skoglund.
The Engagements Series, 1958-1978, primarily reflects the latter portion of Marney's career, during his tenure at Myers Park Baptist Church and at Interpreters' House. Both this series and the Calendars Series testify to Marney's busy schedule of speaking appointments, especially during the Myers Park pastorate. In fact, the church hired a full-time administrator to aid in managing the daily activities of the church. Marney preached at major colleges, universities, and seminaries across the United States, including Harvard University, Yale University, and Duke University. He accepted a variety of speaking engagements including the Chautauqua Institute in New York; the Massanetta Center in Virginia; worship services; conferences and symposia; religious organizations, such as Temple Beth El Sisterhood; retreats; and the North Carolina Council of Churches. In addition, Marney spoke at military installations, the Southern Textile Association, and various secular organizations and clubs, such as the Chamber of Commerce, Sertoma Club, and YMCA.
Two major topics in the Subject Series are the Christian Century Foundation, of which Marney was a trustee, and the Ministers and Missionaries Benefit Board of the American Baptist Convention. These two topics overlap with files in the Correspondence Series. Other files of interest include Abingdon Press, the Boy Scouts of America, the Committee on Religion in Appalachia, First Baptist Church (Austin), Myers Park Baptist Church, and the Southern Baptist Theological Seminary. There is also a mimeographed copy of a diary (prepared from tapes), 1954, Sept.-Nov., that Marney wrote on a trip to Korea and Japan, as part of a preaching mission for the Army and Air Force in the Far East.
The President's National Advisory Commission on Rural Poverty Series contains reports on aspects of rural poverty, such as economics, education, conservation and development of natural resources, health and medical care, government, housing, and farming.
The Southern Baptist Theological Seminary Series includes notes on such topics as Christian missions, church history, theology, and Old and New Testament studies. An early volume, 1899-1902, contains notes for a class by W. O. Carver on Christian missions.
The Notes Series contains notes Marney made from the works of various theologians and other authors, such as F.S.C. Northrop, Hans Reichenbach, A. C. Reid, Paul Tillich, Harold H. Titus, Arnold J. Toynbee, and Alfred North Whitehead.
In the Audiovisual Series features sermons, lectures, and books in the following formats: cassette tapes, reel-to-reel tapes, and motion picture films. Of particular interest are the series of reel-to-reel tapes of Laymen's Hour recordings and the Massanetta Springs Recordings made by Marney. The Laymen's Hour was a radio broadcast; most of the recordings in this series are in 1965, with one in 1962. Massanetta Springs, Inc. is the Conference Center of the Synod of Virginia, Presbyterian Church, U. S., located near Harrisonburg, Va. These recordings, 1957-1974, were a series of annual lectures at Bible conferences at the center. Originals are closed to use, but listening copies are available for many of the recordings; otherwise staff need to arrange to have use copies made. Please consult with Research Services staff before coming to use this collection.
1. John J. Carey,
Carlyle Marney: A Pilgrim's Progress(Macon, Ga.: Mercer University Press, 1980), p. 36.
Death of God theology; Baptists -- United States -- Clergy; Motion pictures (visual works); Sermons, American; Prejudices; Rural poor; Diaries; Baptists -- Texas; Sound recordings; Baptists -- North Carolina; Korea -- Description and travel; Japan -- Description and travel; Photographs; Southern States -- Religious life and customs; Southern States -- Race relations; American Baptist Convention; Abingdon Press; Church and Race Conference (Charlotte, N.C.); Christian Century Convention; Coffin, William Sloan; Cleland, James T., 1903-1978; Duncan, Pope A., 1920-; Committee on Religion in Appalachia; Kilgore, William J. (William Jackson) 1917-; King, Martin Luther, Jr., 1929-1968; Edge, Findley, 1916-; Golden, Harry; Moyers, Bill D.; President's National Advisory Committee on Rural Poverty; Menninger, Karl, 1893-; Trueblood Elton, 1900-; Ranson, Guy 1916-; Southern Baptist Theological Seminary (Louisville, Ky.)
- Correspondence Series, circa 1945-1978
  Scope and Contents note
  Chiefly professional letters of the late 1950s to 1970s received and copies of letters sent, as well as memoranda, alphabetically arranged by correspondent and chronologically arranged within the correspondent's file. Also contains miscellaneous attachments and other non-correspondence mailed to or collected by Marney, such as press releases, organizational charts, leaflets, bulletins, financial records, clippings, writings, and newsletters. In cases of correspondence with a prominent individual, or extensive correspondence with an individual or organization, a separate file has been maintained, for example the American Baptist Convention. Includes several files for Marney family members. This series may contain sensitive materials pertaining to various associates of Marney. Note the statement on the title page concerning this issue.
  - Aa-Al, 1954-1978 (Box 1)
  - Am-An, 1958-1978 (Box 1)
  - Ao-Ar, 1958-1976 (Box 1)
  - As-Az, 1958-1977 (Box 1)
  - Abingdon Press: General, 1948-1958, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Abingdon Press: General, 1959-1978, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Abingdon Press: Bucke, Dr. Emory Stevens, 1957-1978 (Box 2)
  - Abingdon Press: Ellis, Pierce, 1955-1977, 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Abingdon Press: Book Promotion and Itinerary, 1957-1964, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Abingdon Press: Book Promotion and Itinerary, 1965-1970 (Box 3)
  - Abingdon Press: Religion in Life, 1961-1978, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Abingdon Press: Religion in Life, Minutes and Agendas of the board, 1964-1971 (Box 3)
  - Academy of Parish Clergy (Honorary Board), 1975 (Box 3)
  - Adams, Theodore, 1958-1967 (Box 3)
  - Adaire, James, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Alazraqui, Nina, 1960-1967 (Box 3)
  - Albright, H.D., 1966-1967 (Box 3)
  - Alexander, David, 1958-1959 (Box 3)
  - Alexander, Ralph, 1967-1971 (Box 3)
  - Alexander, Stanley, 1966-1977 (Box 4)
  - Almond, Lucy, 1959-1961 (Box 4)
  - Alsdurf, Edna, 1965-1968 (Box 4)
  - Amen, Paul and Henry, 1960-1978 (Box 4)
  - American Baptist Communications, 1962-1968 (Box 4)
  - American Baptist Convention: Conference of Oct. 17-18, 1966 (Box 4)
  - American Baptist Convention: Conference of Mar. 27-29, 1967 (Box 4)
  - American Baptist Convention: England, Martin, 1958-1975 (Box 4)
  - American Baptist Convention: Hansen, Clifford, 1961-1966 (Box 4)
  - American Baptist Convention: Ministers and Missionaries Benefit Board, 1961-1967 (Box 4)
  - American Baptist Convention: Miscellaneous, 1959-1967, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - American Bible Society, 1958-1965 (Box 5)
  - Anderson, Jim, 1970-1972 (Box 5)
  - Andrews, Ed, 1965-1973 (Box 5)
  - Andrews, W.H., 1958-1960 (Box 5)
  - Argo, Monie, 1959-1967 (Box 5)
  - Association of Southern Baptists for Scouting: Carrington, Joe, 1958-1977, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Association of Southern Baptists for Scouting: Flint, Cort, 1959-1960 (Box 6)
  - Austin, Bill, 1961-1964 (Box 6)
  - Avent, George, 1960 (Box 6)
  - Ba-Baq, 1954-1977 (Box 6)
  - Bar, 1958-1978 (Box 6)
  - Bas-Bay, 1958-1977 (Box 6)
  - Bea-Bel, 1958-1974 (Box 6)
  - Bem-Bez, 1954-1976 (Box 6)
  - Bi-Bl, 1958-1977 (Box 6)
  - Bo, 1958-1978 (Box 6)
  - Bra-Bri, 1954-1977 (Box 7)
  - Bro, 1958-1977 (Box 7)
  - Bru-Bun, 1958-1977 (Box 7)
  - Bur-By, 1954-1976 (Box 7)
  - Bailey, Robert, 1975-1977 (Box 7)
  - Baird, Dr. and Mrs. Haynes, 1964-1970 (Box 7)
  - Baker, Bobbie, 1963-1966 (Box 7)
  - Baker, John, 1958-1965 (Box 7)
  - Baker, Robert, 1970- 1972 (Box 7)
  - Baptist Unity Committee, 1962-1964 (Box 7)
  - Barlett, Gene E. 1958-1967 (Box 7)
  - Barnhardt, William, 1958-1971 (Box 7)
  - Barnhart, Joe, 1960-1968 (Box 7)
  - Barrett, George, 1965-1967 (Box 7)
  - Bash, Lawerence, 1959-1963 (Box 7)
  - Bates, Carl E., 1959-1967 (Box 8)
  - Bausmum, Henry S. and Doloris (Box 8)
  - Beebe, Judy 1969-1976 (Box 8)
  - Belk, Eleanor, 1961-1976 (Box 8)
  - Bell, Paul C. Jr., 1961-1963 (Box 8)
  - Berman, Alice and Michael, 1960-1970 (Box 8)
  - Berstein, Mark, 1969 (Box 8)
  - Berry, James A., 1962-1972 (Box 8)
  - Bingham, Darris, 1957-1958 (Box 8)
  - Bininger, Clem E., 1973-1975 (Box 8)
  - Bishop. Elmer, 1955-1958 (Box 8)
  - Blackburn, Glen, 1959-1967 (Box 8)
  - Blackwell, Albert, 1962-1963 (Box 8)
  - Blackwell, Gordon, 1966 (Box 8)
  - Blair, Thom, 1959-1974 (Box 8)
  - Blakemore, Barnett, 1960-1961 (Box 8)
  - Blankenship, Mercer, 1958-1959 (Box 8)
  - Blanton Sanley, 1959-1964 (Box 8)
  - Bobbitt, David, 1962-1963 (Box 8)
  - Bolton, William, 1961-1965 (Box 8)
  - Boone, Walter, 1969-1970 (Box 8)
  - Bosley, Harold, 1959-1967 (Box 8)
  - Bowen, W. A., 1963-1966 (Box 8)
  - Bowman, Burt J., 1960 (Box 8)
  - Boyles, Jack E. 1960-1976 (Box 8)
  - Bramlette, Howard, 1958-1973 (Box 9)
  - Branch, Douglas M., 1960 (Box 9)
  - Bratcher, E.B., 1958-1974 (Box 9)
  - Bratcher, Lewis, 1960-1971 (Box 9)
  - Bridges, J.H., 1958-1973 (Box 9)
  - Bridgman, Ralph 1971-1975 (Box 9)
  - Broach, Claude, 1959-1965 (Box 9)
  - Brooks, Martin C. 1965 (Box 9)
  - Broughton, Tom, 1958-1975 (Box 9)
  - Brown, Arthur, 1959-1966 (Box 9)
  - Brown, Mr. and Mrs. Charles, 1967-1968 (Box 9)
  - Brown, Glen W., 1964-1968 (Box 9)
  - Bryan, Clyde C. 1961-1963 (Box 9)
  - Bryan, Harry H., 1965-1967 (Box 9)
  - Bryan, Mcleod G., 1958-1967 (Box 9)
  - Bryant, Don 1959-1978 (Box 9)
  - Bryant, Mr. and Mrs. James R. Jr., 1959-1977 (Box 9)
  - Bryant, James R. Sr. 1958-1969 (Box 9)
  - Bryson, Howard, 1963-1964 (Box 9)
  - Buchanan, John, 1960-1964 (Box 9)
  - Buchlender, Sam and Antonia, 1961-1970 (Box 9)
  - Burkhead, Mike, 1974-1976 (Box 9)
  - Burnside, Mr. and Mrs. Edward J. Sr., 1959-1969 (Box 9)
  - Burts, Mr. and Mrs. Charles W., 1960-1963 (Box 9)
  - Buttrick, George, 1960-1968 (Box 9)
  - Ca-Carr, 1957-1978 (Box 10)
  - Cars-Caz, 1959-1976 (Box 10)
  - Ce-Ch, 1954-1978 (Box 10)
  - Ci-Cl, 1959-1975 (Box 10)
  - Co-Cop, 1954-1978 (Box 10)
  - Cor-Cr, 1954-1978 (Box 10)
  - Cu. 1959-1977 (Box 10)
  - Cabaniss, Don, 1965 (Box 11)
  - Cain, Lee and Pat, 1960-1965 (Box 11)
  - Calamas, Bill, 1962 (Box 11)
  - Campbell, Ernest, 1962-1966 (Box 11)
  - Carr, Warren, 1958-1977 (Box 11)
  - Carroll, Archie, 1960-1965 (Box 11)
  - Carson, Helen Gates, 1971-1977 (Box 11)
  - Carson, Jack, 1962 (Box 11)
  - Carson-Newman College, 1958-1959 (Box 11)
  - Carswell, Guy T. 1958-1966 (Box 11)
  - Carter, Carrol, 1960-1967 (Box 11)
  - Carter, Theodore, 1959-1963 (Box 11)
  - Casebier, Relly and Elizabeth, 1961-1971 (Box 11)
  - Cash, Mike, 1975-1978 (Box 11)
  - Cason, John W., 1963-1964 (Box 11)
  - CBS News- Childs, P., 1962 (Box 11)
  - CDC (Communicable Disease Center): Rasmussen, Waldrop, 1964) (Box 11)
  - Chalfant, Ruth, 1973-1976 (Box 11)
  - Chandler, Ralph, 1960-1964 (Box 11)
  - Chappell, Wallace, 1964-1977 (Box 11)
  - Charlotte Art Fund, 1963-1965 (Box 11)
  - Charlotte Chamber of Commerce, 1960-1965 (Box 11)
  - Charlotte-Mecklenburg Council on Human Relations, 1965 (Box 11)
  - Cheek, Neal, 1965-1973 (Box 12)
  - Cheshire, John, 1964-1967 (Box 12)
  - Childs, Bob, 1958-1974 (Box 12)
  - Christian Action Council, 1961-1967 (Box 12)
  - The Christian Century Foundation, 1958-1977, 5 folders (Box 12)
  - Christian Faith-and-Life Community, 1958-1961 (Box 13)
  - Christopher, William E. Jr., 1961-1965. (Box 13)
  - Church and Race Conference, Nov. 1962- June, 1965, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Churn, Prentis Jr., 1958-1960 (Box 13)
  - Clark, Robert W., 1960 (Box 13)
  - Clark, Ted R. 1959-1960 (Box 13)
  - Cleland, James T. 1964-1978 (Box 13)
  - Clemons, Mr. and Mrs. Hardy, 1961-1963 (Box 13)
  - Cleveland, C.M., 1954-1963 (Box 13)
  - Cody, Bill B. 1969-1971 (Box 13)
  - Coffin, William Sloan Jr., 1958-1961 (Box 13)
  - Cohen, Henry, 1962-1977 (Box 13)
  - Cole, Newton, 1959-1973 (Box 13)
  - Cone, Bonnie, 1961-1973 (Box 13)
  - Conner, Dick, 1964 (Box 13)
  - Conner, Ruth and Jerry, 1964-1971 (Box 13)
  - Cooksey, Frank, 1959-1976 (Box 14)
  - Cooper, Bill, 1964-1973 (Box 14)
  - Copeland, Herbert, 1959-1976 (Box 14)
  - Corpening, Julius, 1963-1967 (Box 14)
  - Council of Churches (N.C.), 1964-1967 (Box 14)
  - Cowan, Ann, 1967-1969 (Box 14)
  - Craig, Floyd, 1967-1971 (Box 14)
  - Craig, Hellen Eby, 1970-1976 (Box 14)
  - Crandall, Paul Edward, 1964-1975 (Box 14)
  - Crawford, Clarence, 1960-1966 (Box 14)
  - Crawley, Richard, 1962-1974 (Box 14)
  - Creasman, Paul, 1966-1970 (Box 14)
  - Crewse, Gene D., 1967-1973 (Box 14)
  - Croych, Perry W. 1960-1967 (Box 14)
  - Cummings, Bryant, 1964-1975 (Box 14)
  - Cunningham, John R. 1964-1966 (Box 14)
  - Da, 1958-1977 (Box 14)
  - De, 1958-1978 (Box 14)
  - Di-Do, 1954-1978 (Box 15)
  - Dr-Dz, 1958-1978 (Box 15)
  - Daly, George, 1972-1976 (Box 15)
  - Dasher, Bob, 1974-1976 (Box 15)
  - Davidson, John B., 1958-1972 (Box 15)
  - Davis, Carroll, 1973-1975 (Box 15)
  - Davis, Charles D. 1959-1966 (Box 15)
  - Davis, Gibson, 1958-1970 (Box 15)
  - Davis, Robert E. 1958-1963 (Box 15)
  - Davis, William P., 1963-1964 (Box 15)
  - Dean, Kenneth, 1959-1977, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - DeFore, John, 1958-1967 (Box 16)
  - Dehoney, Wayne, 1961-1966 (Box 16)
  - Denham, William, 1958-1975 (Box 16)
  - Denman, Harry, 1960-1966 (Box 16)
  - Dickerson, Jack, 1966 (Box 16)
  - Dickson, Rush, 1958-1975 (Box 16)
  - Diggins, Elemer, 1972-1973 (Box 16)
  - Docherty, George M., 1958-1968 (Box 16)
  - Dove, Mary, 1967 (Box 16)
  - Dowd, Carey III, 1960-1967 (Box 16)
  - Dowd, Mr. and Mrs. Frank Sr., 1961-1975 (Box 16)
  - Dowd, Mr. and Mrs. Frank Jr., 1959-1968 (Box 16)
  - Dowd, Rodney, 1958-1967 (Box 16)
  - Downing, Tom Jr., 1960-1978 (Box 16)
  - Duce, Leonard, 1958-1961 (Box 16)
  - Duke Divinity School, 1972-1978 (Box 16)
  - Duncan, Pope A., 1961-1969 (Box 16)
  - Dunning, Norman, 1963-1964 (Box 16)
  - Dyal, Robert A., 1961-1966 (Box 16)
  - Dykes, Ray, 1958-1960 (Box 16)
  - Ea-Eh, 1958-1976 (Box 17)
  - Ei-Ez, 1954-1978 (Box 17)
  - Early, Tracy, 1958-1973 (Box 17)
  - Edens, David, 1961-1978 (Box 17)
  - Edge, Findley, 1965-1966 (Box 17)
  - Edwards, Ted, 1958-1973 (Box 17)
  - Ellis, Art Marian, 1969-1970 (Box 17)
  - Ellis, Henrietta, 1963-1977 (Box 17)
  - Ellis, Pierce Sr. and Mrs., 1962-1963 (Box 17)
  - Emerck, Sam, 1974-1975 (Box 17)
  - Esser, George, 1970-1977 (Box 17)
  - Eubank, Riley Jr., 1958-1978 (Box 17)
  - Evans, Bruce, 1964-1978 (Box 17)
  - Evans, Joe M. 1958-1966 (Box 17)
  - Fa-Fk, 1958-1977 (Box 18)
  - Fl-Fq, 1958-1976 (Box 18)
  - Fr-Fz, 1954-1977 (Box 18)
  - Fallis, William J., 1958-1961 (Box 18)
  - Farmer, James A., 1959-1961 (Box 18)
  - Ferguson, Irma, 1954-1973 (Box 18)
  - Fillpot, Dave, 1971-1977 (Box 18)
  - Finger, Bill, 1972-1978 (Box 18)
  - Finlator, Bill, 1958-1967 (Box 18)
  - Fite, Harley, 1961-1967 (Box 18)
  - Flaming, James, 1959-1967 (Box 18)
  - Flanders, Lois and Harvey, 1962-1968 (Box 18)
  - Fletcher, Jesse and Dorthey, 1958-1978 (Box 18)
  - Flint, Cort, 1958-1975 (Box 18)
  - Fogartie, James, 1958-1976 (Box 19)
  - Fortenberry, Harriett, 1964-1976 (Box 19)
  - Fost, Frederic, 1959 (Box 19)
  - Fowler, Franklin, 1963-1978 (Box 19)
  - Fowler, James Jr. and Mrs. 1959-1972 (Box 19)
  - Fox, Charles and family, 1958-1966 (Box 19)
  - Francis, Arthur, 1959-1970 (Box 19)
  - Frazier, Claude A., 1973-1974 (Box 19)
  - Freeman, Donald and Ina, 1963-1971 (Box 19)
  - Fridy, Wallace, 1963-1973 (Box 19)
  - From These Stones (The Church Speaks on Race) 1964 (Box 19)
  - Ga-Gd, 1958-1976 (Box 19)
  - Ge-Gk, 1959-1977 (Box 19)
  - Gl-Grh, 1959-1977 (Box 19)
  - Gri-Gz, 1959-1978 (Box 19)
  - Gaddy, Jerrel, 1959 (Box 20)
  - Gaskell, Pete, 1967-1969 (Box 20)
  - Gerber, Isreal J., 1962-1965 (Box 20)
  - Gibson, Mary Ella (Bowers), 1961-1964 (Box 20)
  - Gill, Theodore, 1970-1975 (Box 20)
  - Gilmore, Herbert Jr., 1962-1977 (Box 20)
  - Gilmour, Monroe T., 1967-1971 (Box 20)
  - Ginascol, Frederick (and family), 1958-1976 (Box 20)
  - Goans, Rufus and Sophie, 1967-1975 (Box 20)
  - God is Dead movement, 1966 (Box 20)
  - Goddard, Joe and Mrs., 1961-1966 (Box 20)
  - Godfrey, Fred and Mrs., 1958-1972 (Box 20)
  - Golden, Harry, 1962-1973 (Box 20)
  - Gonzalez, Charlie, 1962-1972 (Box 20)
  - Grant, James, 1972-1973 (Box 20)
  - Grant, Marse, 1964 (Box 20)
  - Grant, Stella, 1965-1974 (Box 20)
  - Grayum, Mrs. Fred A., 1963-1965 (Box 20)
  - Green Lake (American Baptist Assembly), 1959-1960 (Box 20)
  - Greer, Arther E., 1975-1978 (Box 20)
  - Gress, Mark W., 1954-1075 (Box 20)
  - Grigg, W.R., 1959-1967 (Box 20)
  - Grizzard, Stuart and Mrs., 1958-1976 (Box 20)
  - Gross, Paul A. M., 1962-1971 (Box 20)
  - Gumm, Robert K., 1958-1961 (Box 20)
  - Ha-Haq, 1950-1977 (Box 21)
  - Har, 1958-1978 (Box 21)
  - Has-Hem, 1958-1977 (Box 21)
  - Hen-Hh, 1954-1975 (Box 21)
  - Hi-Hols, 1954-1978 (Box 21)
  - Holt-Ht, 1958-1978 (Box 21)
  - Hu-Hz, 1958-1978 (Box 22)
  - Hall, Beach and Susan, 1969-1973 (Box 22)
  - Hall, Carolyn, 1960-1966 (Box 22)
  - Hamner, Rev. Bob, 1958-1964 (Box 22)
  - Hamerick Family, 1965-1978 (Box 22)
  - Hand, Othell, 1959-1967 (Box 22)
  - Harmon, Nolan, 1958-1961 (Box 22)
  - Harrelson, Walter, 1958-1965 (Box 22)
  - Harrington, Tony, 1963-1968 (Box 22)
  - Harris, Douglas J. 1958-1971 (Box 22)
  - Harris, Rufus C., 1959-1976 (Box 22)
  - Harrison, Lea and King, 1959-1977 (Box 22)
  - Hart, Arno, 1959-1975 (Box 22)
  - Hartt, Julian and Neva, 1960-1967 (Box 22)
  - Hathcock, Phil, 1974 - 1978 (Box 22)
  - Hawkins, Aubrey, 1959 (Box 22)
  - Hayes, Barry, 1958-1961 (Box 22)
  - Haynes, Donald, 1969-1970 (Box 22)
  - Haynie, Bill and Joyce, 1958-1960 (Box 22)